hey everybody caffeine man here and
today we're gonna be going over a drink
for the gamers that's right we're gonna
be going over game fueled by Mountain
Dew and amp but not only that I feel
like my timestamps are gonna be highly
used in this video because I'm also
gonna be giving you guys a history
lesson do gamers like history I don't
know but I'm about to find out coming
right up hello again everyone thanks for
joining me today today we're going over
one for the gamers and that's gonna be
game fuel it's been a very popular
request on my channel not to be confused
with G fuel which I probably won't be
reviewing but I'll probably review it in
July when G fuel comes out with the cans
because I prefer the cans as opposed to
powdered drinks so today it's gonna be
game fuel as well as a history lesson
well if your game is want to skip ahead
that's perfectly fine if you want to
learn something I got the info for you
so what's this history lesson gonna be
on glad you asked I'm gonna start off
talking about mountain dew that's right
the one the only the original the first
highly energized soft drink from there
I'm going to talk about its progression
throughout the years leading up to the
time that they came up with amp I'll
talk a little bit about the history of
amp as well and tell me how they dealt
with kickstart also made by mountain dew
and how they decided they were gonna
handle the competition and that'll bring
me up to the modern times when we can
talk about the newest energy drink that
they came up with game fuel by Mountain
Dew amp I'm gonna go over the cherry
burst the berry blast the tropical
strike and the original do time stamps
listed below if you want stay informed
on all these caffeine really feel free
to hit that subscribe button I post new
videos every Tuesday night and I want
you guys to be there also feel free to
follow me on all social media my
instagram twitter facebook linkedin all
at caffeine man one-game fuel is
targeting gamers everywhere just by
simply putting the word game in their
beverage but let's face it the original
game fuel was a drink called Mountain
Dew loved by teens everywhere hated by
parents everywhere teenagers drank the
stuff during any game that they played
whether it was their favorite board game
or even just a video game they had to
have the do now back in the day gaming
wasn't anything like it is now games
just sort of kind of continued on and on
you know you jump over a pit then you
jump over an alligator then you jump
over a pit then you swing over an
alligator then you jump over a pit and
you get the idea there wasn't a lot of
playtime involved but as video
for guests you got lots of hours of
playtime I mean some people take
hundreds of hours to play a game but way
back in the day Mountain Dew was played
for a lot of other games that took a
long time I mean some of these games
people would play for hours and hours
and did I mention they played them for
hours I mean some of these games could
even be played for more than hours they
can be played for days and they could be
played for weeks depending on who was
running the game um can I get back in
the shop please thank you so once video
games start expanding out until longer
play times hardcore gamers also expanded
from Mountain Dew to other energy drinks
such as amp or any other energy drink
for that matter now as you all should
know Mountain Dew is a Pepsi product
what you may not have known is that it
was originally created to be a mixer for
moonshine and whiskey that's right it
was created by two bottlers in Tennessee
Barney and Ally Hartman in the early
1940s Mountain Dew is actually the slang
name by the Scottish and the Irish to
describe moonshine and the Harmon
brothers decided to use that as its
trademark in 1948 in 1960 the Harmon
brothers teamed up with a company called
the tip corporation in 1961 the tip
company bought the rights to Mountain
Dew and Bill Bridge fourth a manager at
the plant at the time decided to start
putting his own tri-city lemonade into
the mountain dew and that caused sales
to take off I mean they skyrocketed for
the company in going with the citrus
lemonade idea Mountain Dew decided that
more citrus was the way to go on the
back of the bottle or the can you'll
find that concentrated orange juice high
fructose corn syrup and citric acid are
three of the key ingredients in 1964
PepsiCo purchased the tip corporation
and thus required the race to Mountain
Dew and the rest is pretty much history
since its inception
Mountain Dew has come up with over 40
different flavors over the years some
are still with us many have gone away
has that affected the sales some
theorize that it has the reason being
that sometimes people actually love
certain flavors but if they don't
perform that well or as well as the
company wanted them to they'll pull them
off the market and if you do that enough
times you can have enough people that
liked lots of different beverages that
you made and then you just took him away
from them and those people are gonna be
more skeptical to try out a new drink
when it comes out only to have it
potentially taken away so as much as
it's always good
try and come up with new ideas they came
up with a lot of new ideas but pulled a
lot of them back from people which
potentially hurts them in the future
a 16-ounce bottle of Mountain Dew has 61
grams of sugar and 72 milligrams of
caffeine which comes out to four and a
half million of caffeine per ounce and
then there was AMP Energy Drink
was created under the mountain Dew brand
in the 2001 amp was released onto the
market the original formula of AMP
Energy Drink was marketed as a flavor
extension of the Mountain Dew brand in
the label red lamp energy drink from
Mountain Dew when I first tried amp I
thought that it was just concentrated
Mountain Dew and when they did reviews
on it they just said that it was a
glorified Mountain Dew but to a certain
extent that's kind of what Mountain Dew
was going for they wanted Mountain Dew
as an energy drink but I know that I did
not like it because it was sweet in 2006
only five years after its creation they
decided to change their packaging to
make it more amped up see what I did
there then in 2007 and 2008 they began
releasing new flavors some of the
flavors released were traction elevate
and relaunch in each year after that
they tried to come out with additional
flavors including a few tea flavors as
well in 2009 for the original flavor amp
energy they decided to take off the
mountain Dew logo for another redesigned
can and at that point in 2009 they began
selling amp under its own name in 2012
again amp tried to make a difference in
the market by releasing yet another
series this time it was their active
boost and focused line it basically was
trying to market it based on those buzz
words in 2017 yep energy drink announced
its plans to release amp organic energy
with more natural energy drinks hid in
the market if decided that this was
going to be their perfect opportunity to
get customers what they demanded it only
has a few ingredients in it and those
ingredients are carbonated water organic
cane sugar citric acid natural flavors
inorganic caffeine from natural green
coffee beans
sounds pretty healthy huh well maybe not
all that being said the 12 ounce can
that he came up with still had 44 grams
of sugar in it granted it was pure cane
sugar the healthier of the sugars but
still 44 grams and that 12 ounce can is
a lot of sugar but then again as what
Mountain Dew is known for as for
caffeine the organic energy drink series
was a
I can't and I had 120 milligrams of
caffeine in it putting it at 10
milligrams per ounce just like the
standard amount of the most common
energy drinks on the market that's for a
regular amp it's a little bit weird the
16 ounce can only has a hundred and
forty-two milligrams of caffeine in it
so it's actually less than 10 milligrams
per ounce also it only has about 20
percent of your daily value of all the B
vitamins but most importantly it's got
58 grams of sugar in it that makes it
one of the highest sugar content and
energy drinks on the market and is just
beating out venom and monster by a
little bit and the only ones that are
higher than it are ones like rip it a
handful of the rockstar flavors no fear
and a few other smaller independent
companies but then again Mountain Dew
has always been known for the highest
amount of sugar and their drinks
so why not energy drinks too with all
this talk of Mountain Dew and amp
what about kickstart doesn't about we do
also make kickstart isn't that like a
conflict of interest
well with amp finally taking Mountain
Dew off the logo in 2009 yep it's slowly
been pushing itself away from his
association with Mountain Dew even
though we all know it was still owned by
Pepsi and Mountain Dew I mean they must
have hoped that other people forgot it
as well because in February of 2013
Mountain Dew announced its new energy
drink called kickstart now they didn't
actually want to compete with amp since
they were the same company but they
still wanted to tap into the energy
drink world a little more when it was
released
Pepsi actually stated that kickstart
wasn't an energy drink but an enhanced
soft drink they believe that Mountain
Dew lovers return to this beverage as a
healthier breakfast option instead of
regular Mountain Dew because people
drink Mountain Dew for breakfast energy
drink breakfast beverage that's what
you're going with kickstart I mean I
don't know about you but I don't know
anyone who drinks an energy drink for
breakfast
besides well me but when I do have an
energy drink in the morning it's not for
breakfast
and usually okay sometimes it is anyway
it sounded ridiculous to most people I'm
sure I mean don't you agree comment down
below if you guys drink energy drinks
for breakfast and then that's it I'd
love to know that I'm not the only one I
know some of you probably do it in the
morning for a pre-workout and that could
be your breakfast as well all that being
said depending on which kickstart you
picked up regular Kickstarter has 5%
fruit juice in it and hydrating boost
has 10% fruit juice in it my new
kickstart also has some vitamin
and some vitamin C in it as well how
about caffeine
there's 16 ounce can of this energy
drink has only 92 milligrams of caffeine
in it 92 for a 16 ounce energy drink
that puts it at just under 6 milligrams
per ounce as for sugar it only actually
has 20 grams of sugar so maybe they're
learning maybe not as I said Mountain
Dew actually came out with over 40
different flavors in their time as for a
champ they keep trying to recreate
themselves every couple of years by
rebranding themselves and come out with
new logos and new cans and look we're
new and then slightly changing up their
flavors and even though they constantly
try and reinvent themselves they haven't
been doing a bad job overall between the
years of 2009 in 2013 HAMP was holding
strong as being the fourth or fifth
ranking energy drink on the market now I
say that's pretty good I know all
companies strive to be the best but
there's no way that Mountain Dew or AMP
is actually gonna be able to compete
with your big names like Red Bull and
monster and either the up and rising
bang right now but they can keep trying
if they want now what they really need
to do is get rid of all those other
companies all those other brands and all
those other flavors and focus on just
one drink if they can focus on one drink
maybe they'd have some success and limit
the amount of flavors - because you got
way too many flavors focus on just a few
drinks and you could be successful is
game fuel gonna be that drink it might
be my own do didn't mind having its name
on amp to help them out
they eventually pulled away and decided
to let amp stand on its own two feet
then Mountain Dew experimented with
kickstart they did alright well now game
fuel it's got three logos on it it's got
Matt wouldn't do it's got amp and it's
got game fuel mountain dew amp game fuel
going back to their beginnings with as
many logos as they can to sell the brand
so enough with the history lesson let's
get back to modern times and take an
in-depth look at game fuel first off
this 16-ounce can has 90 milligrams of
caffeine boom strike one game fuel 99
tea in a 16 ounce can that's like five
and a half milligrams per ounce I mean
coffee is stronger than that I mean come
on a 16 ounce can of Mountain Dew a soda
has 72 milligrams
caffeine in it do you really think
you're gonna be that competitive in the
energy drink market when you can't even
come in at the standard 10 milligrams
per ounce Jace come on let's take a look
at the can total sugar 23 grams not bad
for a mountain Dew product added sugar
20 grams a bit high 40% of your daily
value carbs are at 24 which is 90
percent of your daily value
it's got 20% of your vitamin A forty
percent your daily value of niacin 40
percent your daily value for b6 and 40%
for Panathenaic acid which is your b5
not too bad but still kinda low for the
amount of vitamins in most energy drinks
for sweeteners it uses high fructose
corn syrup sucralose and a sulphate
potassium as for their ingredients well
there's a bunch in there but some of the
noteworthy ones are l-theanine which I'm
a huge fan of panax ginseng root extract
which I'm also a fan of your Bharati
extract which I'm also a fan of and the
cherry burst uses red for tea why do I
care about red for tea well research
studies have actually shown and proven
that it can cause hyperactivity in
children maybe that's why they put it in
there lots of other testing has been
done on red for tea but nothing bad has
been conclusive for humans just a few
negative side effects in rats all right
guys let's try these out see how game
fuel does excited let's start off with
the original do my best guess is that
it's gonna be similar to Mountain Dew
probably similar to amp with its own
game fuel kick to it and as a side note
these got some really cool tops to them
it's meant to be opened and then slid
back but then it also be slid forward so
that it's resealable so actually when
you saw the nutrition packs on the can
they give you the one serving size and
then they give you the nutrition facts
for the whole can unlike some of the
other energy drink companies like
monster who just give you the numbers
for one serving but it's two servings
per can this actually gives you both
options and because it's resealable you
can actually drink half the can if you
want close it up and save it for later I
like it let's see how easy it is to open
though it actually has instructions on
the top hand on the side of the can to
how helpful
pull here that's kind of pop to it then
slide back nice
well look at that color
whoo do that that has four recen right
there let's try it out
Wow
yeah I mean that tastes like a strong
Mountain Dew I mean I'm actually right
now considering trying of the amp and
Mountain Dew just to compare it to I
have one around I put one up there you
guys want me to try it out I wasn't
planning on doing this that's why I'm
unprepared I'm actually gonna do it I'll
put this one down here I'll go grab that
one
[Music]
yes I know it is warm but you know in
times of need
let's compare the two oh man I mean
they're almost so similar I mean I were
related to Pantone colors but you guys
probably wouldn't know what I was
talking about yes they're pretty similar
this definitely has a soda flavor to it
because it's Mountain Dew soda and this
one has more of the energy drink flavor
to it but it's Mountain Dew energy drink
I mean they call it the original do and
they weren't lying if you like my own do
and you want some more caffeine not a
lot more caffeine but 20-something odd
milligrams you'll be all set move along
next up we'll try the tropical strike
some of you may have noticed that
they're actually all called charged so
this is charged tropical strike the
other one is charged cherry burst the
other one is charged original do and the
last one is charged berry blast
I think that's stupid so I'm not calling
them that tropical strike these things
really pop be careful when you open
these you didn't let a little mist
coming at ya and smell the chocolate
although as I pour it oh my goodness
you're that these things are fluorescent
all right
hate to see my pee later I talk about
pee too much I might Wow that is
actually a really good tropical flavor I
get some pineapple in there pineapples
probably the strongest I guess some
mango in there a little bit of orange a
little bit of citrus going on in there
as well I really liking it I mean I
should probably do a comparison video
because I like the Red Bull tropical
I've had some other energy drinks that
are tropical as well that have been
pretty good and this is right up there
with a good tropical flavor if you guys
like tropical you like the pineapple you
like the orange mango all that tropical
stuff you're gonna like this they are a
little bit sweet but they're not too
sweet I'm quite surprised by it because
I always expect Mountain Dew to be extra
sweet and even though these are sweet
trust me they're not not sweet but
they're not banging and rain sweet
they're just right under that
and maybe like under venom as well
because that was really sweet but with
only 23 grams of sugar they must use a
decent amount circle oats as well as
well as that Assam something potassium
hey don't look up what that stuff was
I'm lazy I mean I had to look up all the
stuff for a whole entire a history
lesson to the history mountain do it to
the history of a mr. kickstart did
kickstart vs. amp I started to fit time
in for an energy drink review hey I
drink all these things super quick
hopefully get this video down under who
knows how many minutes how many minutes
is this videos leave me a long video
especially if you keep talking like this
I shouldn't drink the energy drink
before I stop the video I usually drink
the energy drink before the stop the
video to get me up a little bit to keep
me going but then I drink four or five
energy drinks turn on the energy now I'm
just babbling okay I'm moving on zydeco
tropical very good if you like tropical
I highly suggest you try this out it's
good moving on next up we got the cherry
burst vegetable cherry goodness at least
I hope so now be careful now this
thing's gonna spray all over me make
sure you hold that part away from your
face so it goes that way because if you
open it this way we'd have to open it
with your thumb to open it this way but
yeah open it this way that's kind of fun
let me down with those bold colors my
goodness that's some bold red there some
cherry red we're going three for three
it's a little bit sweet but it's not a
bad sweet coz I'm a sucker for sweet
stuff got a good cherry flavor I mean I
mean I'm talking from all the cherry
drinks that I've had so it's got a
strong solid cherry flavor to it really
got some pop to it but I am tasting a
little aftertaste of something now I
still got the cherry flavor but I'm have
to sip again I didn't even take a second
sip of the other ones did I now remember
hmm yeah something a little bit weird
about it I can't put my finger on it I
think it might actually be the sucralose
flavor so it is a bit sweet probably a
little bit sweeter than the other two I
think they might have had just a little
bit too much sucralose in it because I'm
getting some of that sucralose flavor
not to say the super low flavor is bad
but you get this nice solid cherry
flavor and then you get this aftertaste
of sucralose
some people don't mind the sucralose but
any time an energy
has an aftertaste and it's not the
aftertaste of something good it's a
little off-putting so this one's gonna
be the bottom of my list so far for the
game fuels it's got a good cherry flavor
but that aftertaste is gonna hit me if
you don't mind aftertaste you might like
it as always I always say try it out for
yourself if you don't like it don't
drink it again don't believe me if you
didn't like it cuz I warned you moving
on to the blue last but certainly not
least the berry blast I am a sucker for
a good berry and I'm hoping for the best
because the first two were good
the third one not so good and berries
always my favorite so let's get right to
it
watch out for opening it cuz it explodes
I can only imagine if you shook these
like a little bit okay what do you guys
do it I want to know how it goes I want
you to shake it up just a little bit or
a lot and see how much it explodes
because these things explode just by
holding them watch this I'm actually
gonna open this one closer to the camera
do you see that did you see that
nuts cool ooh baby I love you singing a
song no copyright infringement please I
am NOT copyright infringement we know
the song hey that wasn't a song I was
just talking about cool flavor oh yeah
didn't let me down that's a nice good
blueberry it's got a little bit of
raspberry to it it's not too sweet but
it's up there and I'm waiting for that
little sucralose flavor to see if I'm
getting that aftertaste and no I'm not
really getting the super Louis
aftertaste as much as the cherry I might
be tasting it a little bit but yeah it's
actually pretty good it's a good
blueberry good raspberry mix might have
a hint of some other berry in there but
overall it's blue meaning that it's
blueberry with lower raspberry it's a
berry blast it doesn't lie I gotta say
they're very straightforward with their
colors and their flavors and they were
dead-on they started off with four
flavors and they nailed each one of
those flavors cherry has a little
sucrose butter and actually believe it
or not out of the four of them I
probably the tropical
best even though this berry is pretty
good that tropical got all my taste buds
going between the pineapple the orange
the mango all the flavors that were in
there on the forum might be picking that
one up again maybe this one too now
earlier I did poke fun at the fact that
these only have 90 milligrams of
caffeine in them but honestly if they're
actually marketing these to gamers and
gamers primarily of teenagers and don't
get mad in the comments down below I
know there are plenty of adults that
play games as well whether they're
marketing it to gamers and then
marketing it to teenagers because it's
Mountain Dew a lot of people don't know
this but the average amount of caffeine
that a child is supposed to take in and
that's anywhere between 12 and 18 years
old is between 100 and 150 milligrams
the hunt death allure age closer to 150
as you get closer to that 18 limit once
you turn 18 you can magically go to 400
safely a day but until then you're
supposed to stay under 150 these energy
drinks with only 90 we're gonna keep the
gamers under that amount which is quite
genius on their part I must say and only
90 milligrams they'll be able to drink
this safely play their game for as long
as they want get the caffeine they need
get some B vitamins and C vitamins B all
set to go add that to the flavors being
really good it's gonna make it appealing
for a lot of mountain dew people don't
want to step it up from Mountain Dew and
get away from amp
I think game fuels got a hit on their
hands right here not just this one all
four of them I mean men v in the market
they're not gonna catch up the red bull
or monster but I'm predicting in 2020
man would do amp game fuel could hit
that number three spot I have to see how
bang does bang doesn't have the
distribution out there yet my own do
game fuel Pepsi second best distributor
in the world not gonna mention the other
one I think they can do it alright so
that's all I got for you guys today I'm
gonna go run some laps right now maybe
even clean the house who knows I should
probably just go to the gym but I don't
have a gym membership don't plan on it
so until next Tuesday you guys have
yourselves a great day or night
you